

# Sylvain **Delahaies**

Data Science | Data Engineering



#### - In brief —

After more than ten years of applied and fondamental research in Mathematics and Data Assimilation, I decided to operate a slight career shift to embrace the AI revolution. Starting with an intensive self-training in Machine Learning and Deep Learning, I then joined DataScientest to train as a Data Engineer to fulfill my potential.

My goal: to design, implement and deploy AI solutions.

# In practice -



in sylvaindelahaies

Condat-sur-Vézère, Dordogne, FR



partial/full-remote working

### Languages -

- French Mother tongue
- # English professional proficiency
- German Notions

# - Education -

- PhD 2005-2008
   Contact and Complex structures in Geophysical Fluid Dynamics
   University of Surrey
- MSc 2004-2005 Hydro-Informatics University of Surrey
- MSc 1999-2004
   Mathématiques et Applications
   Université d'Angers

#### Interests —

- City council
   Computing
- Sciences Linux
- Technologies
   craft building
- Piano, Guitar Hiking
- Lutherie Heritage

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Math & Data Science**

- Geophysical Fluid dynamics
- Data analysis & visualisation
- Data assimilation
- Machine Learning
- Computer Vision
- Natural Language Processing
- Reinforcement Learning
- Recommendation System

# **Languages & Tools**

- python, bash, ŁTĘX, Git, Matlab
- pytorch, tensorflow, sklearn
- VS code, jupyter, Android Studio

#### **Isolation & Orchestration**

- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Airflow

#### **Databases**

- SQL & NOSQL
- MongoDB
- ElasticSearch
- Neo4i

## Big Data

- Java Spark
- Pyspark
- Hadoop Hive
- Kafka
- Spark Streaming

## Development

- Fastapi
- Flask
- Dash
- Streamlit
- Django

# **TRAINING**

# **Data Engineer**

**Datascientest** Diploma certified by les MINES ParisTech-full-remote Programming, Databases, Machine learning, Big Data, Streaming, Automation, Deployment, Devops.

**Project:** Development of a travel planning App with POI recommendation: design, implementation, deployement.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Visiting Research Fellow
University of Surrey - full-remote

2020-present Guildford, UK

2023

# **Post-doctoral Research Assistant**

University of Surrey - full-remote

2009-2020 Guildford, UK

2011-2012

- **★ Data Assimilation and Stochastic Point Processes**
- Development of Bayesian filters, deployment on HPC.
- Application to crime modeling, social and neural networks, Covid19 outbreak.
- Machine learning for the assessment of insurance risks associated with land subsidence.
- Development of a flask/dash web app to monitor the evolution of the Covid19 outbreak.

# \* Data Assimilation and Terrestrial Ecosystems

- Development of variational methods for the analysis of the Carbon cycle for terrestrial ecosystems.
- Study of very high resolution satellite imagery together with a terrestrial ecosystem Carbon cycle model to monitor and detect forest degradation.
- Development of variational tools to evaluate the information content of different observation fluxes in Carbon cycle models.
- Development of a matlab interface to analyse the sensitivity for Carbon cycle models.
- \* Teaching: Numerical soultions for PDEs
- **★ Communication:** publications, posters, conferences, seminars.